An epic fantasy of peace and magic.
Wizards is a animation, fantasy, science fiction film directed by Ralph Bakshi.
After the death of his mother, evil mutant wizard Blackwolf
discovers long-lost military technologies.
Full of ego and ambition, Blackwolf claims his mother's throne,
assembles an army, and sets out to brainwash and conquer Earth.
Meanwhile, Blackwolf's gentle twin brother, the bearded sage Avatar, calls upon his own magical abilities to foil
Blackwolf's plans for world domination — even if it means eliminating his own flesh and blood.
Avatar (voice), played by Bob Holt.
Elinore (voice), played by Jesse Welles.
Weehawk (voice), played by Richard Romanus.
Peace (voice), played by David Proval.
Sean (voice), played by Mark Hamill.
President (voice), played by Jim Connell.
Wizards is a 1977 American animated post-apocalyptic science fantasy film written,
directed and produced by Ralph Bakshi and distributed by 20th Century-Fox.
The film follows a battle between two wizards of opposing powers, one representing the
forces of magic and the other representing the forces of technology.
The film is notable for being the first fantasy film by Bakshi, a filmmaker who was previously known only
for "urban films" such as Fritz the Cat (1972), Heavy Traffic (1973) and Coonskin (1975).
The film grossed US$9 million theatrically with a $2 million budget.
The film explores themes of assassin, nazi, elves, magic, technology.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking and mind_bending.